# **Aaron Noel De Leon**

Creating Impact through Good Code and Thoughtful Design

nelonoel

### SUMMARY

I'm an experienced web developer focusing on front-end development and UI design. I've worked with local and global startups; designing and implementing web apps from the ground up, and publishing regular updates for thousands of users.

#### EXPERIENCE

Phaxio • Front-end Developer & Designer • Mar 2016 - Present

Redesigned and developed Phaxio's branding, marketing website and web app (www.phaxio.com). Centered the design around content, retained previous URLs and made the website responsive (SEO); resulting to about 400% increase in page views in just two months.

Bugwolf • Software Engineer • Jul 2016 - Dec 2016

Developed the Capture app (www.bugwolf.com/capture) – a bug-tracking screen cast app that integrates with 3rd-party storage and issue-tracking services.

- Re-architected the source to make automated builds and updates seamless.
- Added audio recording, multi-screen support, & cursor tracking. Fixed UI and transcoding bugs.
- Structured 3rd-party service integrations and added support for major partners (Dropbox, OneDrive, Google Drive, Github)
- Used React, Electron (Chromium API + NodeJS), Webpack and RecordRTC.

💸 X-Team • Software Engineer & UI Designer • Jun 2016 - Present

Designed and developed a web app (join.x-team.com) to automate the company's initial vetting process, making the applicant review process at least 8× more efficient by weeding out unserious applicants, and automatically indexing applicant details.

↑ Vyllage • Front-end Developer & UI Designer • Feb 2015 - Jan 2016

Lead the redesign and front-end implementation of Vyllage (<u>www.vyllage.com</u>) – a collaborative resumé and job network for universities resulting in 200% increase in sales.

- Designed prototypes and high-fidelity mockups using Sketch and Invision.

- Lead the front-end implementation using SASS and ReactJS and other complementary technologies such as Webpack, Gulp, and Reflux.
- Wrote unit tests for components using Jasmine.

### Voyager Innovations Inc. • Front-end Developer • Jun 2014 - Feb 2015

Developed responsive web apps for local digital products used by thousands of users.

- Smartnet 2.0 (now Safezone): Smart's very own social network, which also aggregates feed from users' social accounts.
- Voyager Developer Portal: Public APIs of Voyager products. (developer.voyagerinnovation.com)
- Takatack: Philippines' online marketplace. (takatack.com)
- Smart Places: a mobile app for location-based reminders and actions.

## UE Research & Development Unit • Team Leader • Jun 2011 - Apr 2014

- Developed software and facilitated system deployments for various university functions. Systems include: Event Registration, University Student Council Election, Pageant Management, Battery Exam Tutorial Enrollment and the UE API.
- Designed and developed web and mobile applications for competitions outside the university. Applications include:
  - Ellen: Chatbot and Community Mobile App (Philippine Commission on Women)
  - The Cooking Colonel: Advertainment Mobile Game (KFC Philippines)
  - Pledgr: Charity Work Recommender (GlobeLabs)
  - Ang Budget Mo (*Your Budget*): Crowd-Sourced National Budget Allocation (Department of Budget Management)
  - phTweet: Filipino Twitter Analytics (TrendMicro)
  - and Casa San Miguel: Charity Organization Website (Philippine Web Designers Organization).
- Facilitated member and non-member trainings about web technologies (PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS), and design (Adobe Photoshop, Fundamental UI/UX Concepts).

#### EDUCATION

**Output University of the East** • April 2014 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Summa Cum Laude GPA: 1.17